

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Senior Administrator seeking roles in System Administration, Citrix
Administration, Windows Server Administration, Configuration Management, Incident
Management, Change Management, Quality Control, BMC Remedy, Technical
Support, Troubleshooting, Installation

Total Experience: 12 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Sc [Computer Science]

Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Designation: Senior Administrator

Current Company: Wipro

Current Location: Chennai
Pref. Location: Chennai

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Role: System Admin

Industry: IT-Hardware & Networking

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Administrator, System Admin, System Administration, Citrix Administration, Windows Server Administration, Configuration Management, Incident Management, Change Management, Quality Control, BMC Remody Technical System Administration, Installation

Remedy, Technical Support, Troubleshooting, Installation

Verified : Number | Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Result-oriented Professional with 12 years of experience in Citrix Administration, Networking, System Administration, Troubleshooting, Installation, Configuration Management, Windows Server Administration, Incident Management, Citrix XenApp, Citrix Xendesktop, BMC Remedy, MCP

To work in an organization where my objective and where my skill can be applied to improve both the organization and to bring out the desired results by working as a team and by bringing out the best of my performance.

Work Experience

Wipro as Senior Administrator Dec 2019 to Till Date

Citrix Administrator managing Farm and implementation

HCL Infra as Senior Specialist -Citrix Administration Apr 2015 to Dec 2019

Citrix XenApp 6.5, 5.0, Presentation server 5.0, Xendesktop Citrix Provisioning Services 5.6

ACTIMITIES

Handling Incidents and attending bridge calls for P1 and P2 tickets.

Doing citrix Servers health check activity.

Installing Server and Implementation of XenApp Environment

Checking offline servers and troubleshooting the issue

Disk cleanup activity for low disk alerts.

Providing access to published applications and server desktops

Publishing applications and server desktops to users.

Adding and removing citrix servers into the farms.

Troubleshooting citrix application connectivity issues to users.

Creating new target device, Device collection and v Disk

Updating v Disk

Technical skills:

PVS master image creation.

Adding additional PVS Target to an existing device collection

Change Implementation, Versioning v disk

Mindtree Ltd as Engineer IMTS.

Nov 2010 to Apr 2015

Analyzed the system and prepared the Citrix application according to the need of the user.

Important

Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

Maintaining high performance systems and networks supporting thousands of users across multiple locations

Natural communicator and Lead Engineer with strong motivational skills; interfaces effectively with upper management,

staff, peers and clients

Experience in handling Citrix Xen-app console

Providing voice over support to Global Customers.

Installing, Configuring and managing Citrix servers. Maintaining and troubleshooting Application issues.

Monitoring the farm reacting to the alerts.

Handling citrix client connections issues to accessing the publishing resources.

Clearing of user profiles

Publishing applications on the Citrix servers as per customer requirement.

Handling Citrix app client Issues

Shadowing users, checking sessions, managing server load and CPU utilization.

Good monitoring and analyzing skill in trouble tickets.

Installation and maintenance Antivirus in Windows environments

Good knowledge in all kinds of troubleshooting with windows system

Nebula Computers Pvt. Ltd. as Desktop L1 Engineer

Dec 2007 to May 2010

L1 Support Engineer for Scope International t Windows 2000/XP/2003 and Vista Role Environment

Complaints Remedy 7.5 Software deployment RADIA

Responsibilities:

Attending User calls for their day-to-day problems

Handling 4000-5000 Hosts in the Scope International

Experience in Handling Customers and Resolve their Issues Experience in Trouble Ticketing Systems in BMC Remedy 5.0

Installing application & Troubleshooting RADIA (HP) software in client.

Have to use Good Communication Skills.

Installation and configuration of Application software's like, IBM Personal Communication, Mainframe applications like AS400, Hogan

Accessing desktops through Remote for Problem Solving.

Troubleshooting and Configuration of Mail clients Issues (outlook, lotus notes)

Citrix applications like FEDS & Configured ICA Settings.

Troubleshooting PCs and Peripherals

Troubleshooting all Network Problems, Laptop Problems.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (Computer Science) from Madras University in 2004

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Windows SERVER 2008 AD (70-640)	2003	2014	2 Year(s)
Citrix XenApp 6.5, 5.0	7.0	2019	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Problem Management	3.0	2016	4 Year(s)
XENDESKTOP	7.11	2019	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Presentation server 5.0			
Citrix Provisioning Services 5.6			

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
Tamil	Expert	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.